Inventory of the Henry Kearns papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Henry Kearns papers
1942-1979
78097
Hoover Institution Archives
42 manuscript boxes, 7 oversize boxes, 5 card file boxes, art objects (19.7 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, office files, and printed matter, relating to international trade and finance policy, and operations of the Export-Import Bank during the Presidency of Richard M. Nixon.
Kearns, Henry, 1911-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Henry Kearns (1911-1985) was an American international finance and business consultant and statesman. He was active in Republican politics on both state and national levels, serving as assistant secretary of commerce for international affairs from 1957 to 1961 and as president and chairman of the Export-Import Bank of the United States from 1969 to 1973.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, office files, and printed matter, relating to international trade and finance policy, and operations of the Export-Import Bank during the Presidency of Richard M. Nixon.
Export-Import Bank of the United States.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Banks and banking, International.; Commerce.; International finance.; United States--Commercial policy.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.
- Alphabetical file
  - Asia Society (Boxes 1)
  - Bills Paid, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
  - Burglary-San Marino, 5/1969 (Box 2)
  - Change of Addresses, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Christmas cards,1969 thru 1973 (Box 2)
  - CREW (Box 2)
  - Dollar Award, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Gifts, Official from Eximbank (Box 2)
  - Gifts Received, Personal, Eximbank (Box 2)
  - Hill Apppointments, Eximbank (during HK tenure) (Box 2)
  - Inauguration - 1973 (Republican Party) (Box 2)
  - Memberships - Inactive (Box 3)
  - Mints, Franklin and U.S. (Box 3)
  - Mitsui Dinner, 6/26/1971 (Box 3)
  - Move, California to D.C., 1969 (Box 3)
  - National Foreign Trade Convention, 10/1/1973 (Box 3)
  - Passport File, Personnel (other than Eximbank) (Box 3)
  - Republican Party (Box 3)
  - SRI, 9/15/1973, 9/23/1973 (Box 3)
  - Thai Bronze Makers (Box 4)
  - Travel, Henry Kearns personal, thru 1973 (Box 3)
  - White House Personnel Referrals (Box 4)
  - Applicants re Henry Kearns replacement (Box 4)
  - Reports for White House, monthly and weekly (Box 4)
- Kearns International file
  General note
  See also Countries Subject file
  - Opening of Kearns International correspondence
    - Follow-up Letters "C," 6/7/74 (Box 4)
    - Congratulations only, responses to 2/20/1974 letter (Box 4)
    - Follow-up, 11/12/1974 (Box 4)
    - Follow-up, Foreign and U.S. (Box 5)
  - United Nations Conference on Trade and Developement (UNCTAD) (Box 6-7)
- Export-Import Bank file
  - Congressional (Box 7-8)
  - Press releases and speech copies (Box 8-9)
  - Articles, Henry Kearns (Box 9-10)
  - Resignation letter and letters received in response (Box 10)
  - Responses to complimentary letters (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Eximbank programs (Box 11)
  - Trip reports (Box 11-12)
  - Executive Personnel (Box 13)
  - Congressional Hearings (Box 13)
  - Briefing book, Economic Studies, 1973 (Box 14)
- Index file of visitors to the office of Henry Kearns during tenure as chairman of Export-Import bank of the United States, April, 1969-October, 1973 (Box 15-19)
- Clippings (Box 20-25)
- Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, business records, legal documents, clippings, and photographs, 1942-1979, relating to U.S. foreign trade policy in the Eisenhower and Nixon administrations, the U.S. Export-Import Bank, business activities of Henry Kearns, and a U.S. Department of Justice investigation of Henry Kearns (Box 26-47)
- Countries subject file
  Various reports by Kearns International, arranged alphabetically by country, either government or private sector.
  - Algeria, Australia, Barbados, Bolivia, Brazil (Box 48)
  - Brazil, Canada, Chile, China (Box 49)
  - Ecuador, El Salvador, Ghana, Gulf States, Indonesia, Ivory Coast, Korea (Box 50)
  - Korea, Kuwait, Latin America and the Caribbean (Box 51)
  - Latin America and the Caribbean, Malaysia, Panama, Philippines, Sudan, Venezuala (Box 52)
- General subject file
  Arranged alphabetically by subject matter.
  - U.S. Government Support for Small Businesses (Box 53)
  - Cement production, worldwide (Box 53)
  - Liquefied Natural Gas, Importation of (Box 53)
  - Power plants, miscellaneous (Box 53)
  - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (Box 53)
- Artwork and memorabilia
  - Korean Panel Screen (Object Room 250)
    Scope and Contents note
    The wall mounted screen is from the early Yi dynasty (1392-1910) and depicts a multitude of military figures in full combat regalia and arranged in formation in colored ink on tan linen with a brocade mat in a wood frame.
  - Two glass exhibit cases; Formerly held amber pieces (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Two wooden boxes containing two black oriental (Thai?) statues (Memorabilia cabinet)